# **Donald Hyde**

Bowdoin, ME 04287 760.492.4726 donald.hyde2@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/donaldhyde https://github.com/donaldhyde

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Front-end Developer with nearly ten years of experience developing software in various capacities including building dynamic, responsive web applications; helping development teams maximize their output through process improvements; developing and managing a product backlog; and collaborating with remotely distributed stakeholders, marketing, sales, design, and engineering teams (both on- and off-shore).

# **KEY SKILLS**

Javascript | React | Redux | Ajax | HTML | CSS | Stylus

Node | Express | Git | NPM | Webpack | PHP WordPress

Agile Development | Unit Testing | Responsive Design | User Experience

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Captive Drone Technologies - Brunswick, ME

Providing training, equipment, and support for the development of in-house UAS programs.

Software Consultant September 2020 - Current

Provide technical direction and prototypes for various projects and integrations.

- Represent Captive Drone's software interests in business partnerships.
- Provide technical expertise, guidance, and estimates for current and future software projects.
- Developed prototypes in Node.js for UAS data consumption to be integrated into partner platform.

## Ingage (Previously ScrollMotion) - San Diego, CA

Transforming sales with industry-leading interactive presentation software.

Product Manager October 2018 - January 2019

Defined and prioritized feature roadmap to deliver high-value products aligned with business needs and goals.

- Facilitated Scrum ceremonies for development team distributed across the U.S. and in Brazil.
- Coached iOS development team in Agile best practices resulting in completion of sprint backlogs.
- Collaborated with test team to cut regression testing from three days to four hours.
- Maintained clarity and confidence in the product roadmap through clear communication with stakeholders.

## **Web Development Manager**

September 2017 - October 2018

Managed high-performance team in the development and delivery of all company web technology.

- Supported Product Manager with backlog management, writing clear and actionable stories and identifying high-value items for upcoming sprints.
- Advocated self-organization methods to achieve accurate estimates and maximize sprint execution.
- Increased team output by coaching developers on when and how to prioritize speed over quality.
- Oversaw code structure and maintainability through regular code reviews and pull requests.
- Identified technical challenges in UI/UX designs and collaborated on solutions.
- Communicated technical issues to non-technical stakeholders

#### **Front-End Developer**

August 2014 - September 2017

Developed web applications and websites with Agile development methodologies.

- Interpreted design specs into requirements for user stories, translated requirements to React code.
- Synchronized development efforts across functional teams, limiting deployment delays.
- Directed onboarding and training of new and junior engineers.
- Achieved 100% analytics coverage for company websites and software using Mixpanel and Google Analytics.
- Developed custom WordPress themes and landing pages.
- Created cross-browser, cross-platform in-line text editing experience.
- Led transition of large enterprise codebase into legacy software and continued maintenance thereafter.

# TV Page - San Diego, CA

Changing online retail with shoppable video storefronts.

Front-End Developer March 2014 - July 2014

Developed web applications and internal frameworks.

• Built templates for web-embeddable video player.

# Ingage (Previously ScrollMotion) - San Diego, CA

#### **Front-End Developer**

February 2011 - February 2014

Built large-scale web applications in an agile environment.

- Designed and built browser-based children's book authoring tool—build on the web, deploy to iOS.
  - Built two new versions of the authoring tool, SmartStudio, based on design specifications—build once, publish to iOS, Android, and Windows
  - Developed custom data guery API for proprietary data format.
  - Wrote conversion scripts to support data versioning upgrades, giving users access to the latest release.
  - Used Jasmine to provide unit test coverage to new and existing code.
  - Strengthened customer support across the company by teaching users how to use SmartStudio software.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO I) - Scrum.org
Professional Scrum Master (PSM I) - Scrum.org

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts - Creative Writing & English, 2019

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH